JONATHAN GREEN

8515 Brodie Lane APT 221 • Austin, TX 78745 • (512) 787-0879 • jgreen1632@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Renewal and sales specialist with 7 years of experience in technology sales, project management, and customer relationship management. Skilled at developing and executing customized solutions to increase market share and provide strategic value to customers. Strong background in public speaking, training, and coaching. Team player and clear communicator with a history of disciplined execution of results.

EXPERIENCE

2020 – Present SolarWinds Austin, TX

Renewal and Sales Specialist II

- Manage a pipeline of 250 accounts per quarter and communicate directly with clients to provide notice of upcoming required maintenance, develop crucial relationships, and identify areas of opportunity to increase sales, achieving 104% of a \$2.4M quota in Q4 2021
- Collaborate with the sales team to coordinate leads, the legal team to create quotes, the finance team to
 adjust pricing negotiation terms, and the engineers and product managers to schedule meetings with clients
 in order to answer questions and ease concerns about product offerings and encourage them to buy
- Selected to be a part of the pilot team for project Helios in 2021 Q3, responsible for developing the full sales cycle for a flagship program including documentation, sales motion, benefits statement, and recommended best-selling tactics
- Designed widgets in NetSuite to streamline processes and track pipeline progress, revenue, and account touches, and mentor new hires, training them on best-selling tactics and account management procedures with a focus on account penetration, organization, and efficiency

2020 Krucial Staffing Overland Park, KS

Inside Management Team – SARS-CoV-2 Response Team

- Managed IT operations for on-location project to staff New York City hospitals with 5,000 nurses during pandemic, involving architecting the computer network to get new office fully operational and establishing technology access and security for 50 employees within seven days, while ensuring HIPPA regulations were met
- Monitored network traffic, managed helpdesk ticket system to investigate and mitigate computer risks and failures, maintained equipment, and performed break/fix analysis and troubleshooting on a 24-hour basis
- Served as liaison between nurses and Inside Management Team, handling onboarding, fit testing for N95
 masks, schedule distribution, and timesheet entry, ensuring nurses were mobilized based on hospital needs

2019 Sterling Computers Corporation Round Rock, TX

Technical Sales Representative

- Collaborated with sales teams and engineers to provide technical sales expertise to understand customer needs, assess equipment and system requirements, analyze and interpret RFQs, provide quotes, and develop solutions to comply with bid specifications for federal government customers
- Developed and presented scopes of work (SOW) and proposals for specific customer requirements, including industry-specific hyperconverged technology solutions
- Prepared and delivered technical presentations explaining products or services to high-profile customers both in-person and virtually
- Followed industry news and trends about legacy, existing, and emerging technologies, and promoted products at trade shows and seminars

 Identified resale opportunities and supported them to achieve sales plans by cultivating relationships, digging deeper to identify needs, and upselling technology to better meet client goals

2017 – 2018 Dell Technologies Round Rock, TX

Technical Sales Representative

- Provided end-to-end enterprise solutions specializing in servers, storage, and networking designed to customer specifications, managing a book of business of 1,132 accounts and a \$1.2M quarterly quota
- Initiated sales campaigns and collaborated with field and inside teams to proactively leverage the CRM to scope, plan, and forecast projects within sales territory
- Prepared sales presentations and proposals to explain product specifications and applications, and developed technical specification questionnaires to ensure customer requirements were met
- Created and delivered virtual and manual training in the implementation and use of new internal software
- Selected as a 'Rover' based upon sales record, rotating among teams to coach and mentor individuals in sales techniques and product knowledge by shadowing calls, explaining technology, and creating training plans
- Awarded \$1.5M contract with a school district for science based VxRail system; advocated for customer to get the best price and product, while also overcoming multiple rounds of negotiations
- Exceeded quota by 246%; inducted into SEAL team for achieving top 1% of sales per year

2016 – 2017 Apple Inc. Austin, TX

Small & Medium Business (SMB) Expert

- Built pipeline of repeat business with 66% customer retention, which involved using a consultative approach
 in qualifying customers to determine technology needed to meet business needs, creating and structuring
 quotes and lease applications, tracking orders, handling supply chain logistics, and analyzing reporting
- Selected among peers, due to retention record, to support two different divisions, simultaneously providing support for order support, returns, shipping investigations and transit logistics
- Sold 20 iMacs to new small business customer, winning the \$200K order by selling the benefits over the Dell equivalent

2015 Lyme Computer Systems Lyme, NH

Solutions for Enterprise-Wide Procurement (SEWP) V Account Manager

- Developed and managed federal contracts and monitored contractor performance, engaging with agencies through NASA SEWP V to build sales pipeline within NASA, FBI, DOVA, CENTCOM, and the White House
- Supported all aspects of the full-cycle federal sales process, from analyzing and interpreting government RFIs, RFPs, RFQs, developing SOWs and quotes, handling purchase and sales orders, invoicing, and providing purchasing and contractual guidance
- Awarded \$2M deal with DOVA, winning the bid over 56 competitors, which involved sourcing a specialized monitor for the contract line item and achieving delivery and installation on time and within budget

2004 – 2009 Conley Enterprises San Marcos, TX

Operations Manager

EDUCATION

Texas State University San Marcos, TX

Bachelor of Arts, Political Science (2013)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Microsoft Access, Word, PowerPoint, Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft Server OS, Salesforce.com, VMware, Enterprise servers, storage, networking, Firewalls, APs, WAPs